Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office audiovisual materials, 1967-2003 and undated RL.11360
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Video Materials, 1967-2003 and undated; 1
  - American Red Cross: Presentation to Southeastern Michigan Region Buddies for Life Campaign, 1988 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-013)
  - American Red Cross Video Network, 1993 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-014)
  - Art of Network Negotiating, Undated (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-015)
  - Art of Network Negotiating, Undated (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-016)
  - Board Meeting Chile, 1988 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-017)
  - board Meeting Italy, 1988 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-018)
    Includes: Kodak, Presto, Osella, Philips, Hunter, Technics, Diamonds
  - Boca Raton Presentation, 1990 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-019)
  - Board of Directors Video, 1993 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-020)
  - BTAA Winners, 1989 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-021)
  - Bullitt chase scene, Undated (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-022)
  - Cannes Winners Part 1, 1993 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-023)
  - Cannes Winners Part 2, 1993 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-024)
  - Channel 4 News--Kinder Essington, 1992 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-025)
  - Channel 4 News--Kinder Essington, 1992 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-026)
  - Channel 7 News with Bill Bonds and Robbie Timmons on Neon Art, 1990 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-027)
  - Channel 7 News with Bill Bonds and Robbie Timmons on Neon Art, 1990 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-028)
  - Co-Op--Doner-Produced work for Champion Spark Plugs, 1983 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-029)
  - Commercials 1948-1982 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-030)
  - Commercials Compilation Reel 2, 1998 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-031)
  - Compilation reel, Undated (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-032)
    Includes: Ford International commercials
  - Compilation reel, Undated (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-033)
    Includes: Ford, Bosch, HAP, Goodyear, Red Cross, Akzo, Teledyne, Reebok, DeBeers, United Way, Kodak, Vic Tanny
  - Compilation reel, 1989 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-034)
    Includes: Ford, Carhartt, Ames, Delta Dental, Bill Knapp, HAP, DPOA, Bosch, Goodyear
  - Compilation reel, 1989 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-035)
  - Compilation reel, Undated (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-036)
    Includes: Monroe, Akzo, Ford, DPOA, Delta Dental, Vic Tanny, United Foundation, Kodak
  - Computer Graphics and Animation, 1993 (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-037)
  - Consumer Behavior--All in the Family Funeral 20:00, Undated (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-038)
  - Creative Campaign Development, Undated (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-039)
  - Creative Campaign Development, Undated (Box 24, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-040)
  - CT-120 GT 4:00, 1986 (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-041)
  - DeBeers spots, 1994 (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-042)
  - Destined to Live, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-043)
  - Detroit Police Officers Association TV News Coverage, 1987 (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-044)
  - Diversified Accounts Reel, 1993 (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-045)
    Includes: FTD, Goodyear, Payless, Vehicle Maintenance Council, Society Bank, Monroe, Walker, Delta Dental, Bosch
  - Douglas Vs. Holyfield, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-046)
  - Dream Cars of the 50s and 60s: Vintage TV Commercials and Sales Films, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-047)
  - Everit Herter International 30:00, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-048)
  - Eyes on Thompson: Steve Davis, Mike Kalasunas, Malachy Walsh, 1993 (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-049)
  - Famous Quotes, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-050)
  - Flippers, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-051)
  - Flippers, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-052)
  - Flippers: Changes in the Way Americans Watch TV, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-053)
  - Focus in Film; Gulp; Little Man on Campus; The Kiss, 2001 (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-054)
  - Ford: 1. Ford and the American Century module and air spots A-39, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-055)
  - Ford: 2. Henry Ford and Wife with Quadracycle, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-056)
  - Ford: 3. Historical Auto Show Background, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-057)
  - Ford: 4. Heritage, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-058)
  - Ford: 5. Outfitters Campaign, Undated (Box 25, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-059)
  - Ford: 6. Global Anthem, Undated (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-060)
  - Ford: 8. 1998-1995 International Reel (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-061)
  - Ford: 9. Car Historical Reel, 1996 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-062)
  - Ford: 10. Car Historical Reel, 1997 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-063)
  - Ford: 11. Car Historical Reel, 1998 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-064)
  - Ford: 12. Truck Historical Reel, 1996 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-065)
  - Ford: 13. Truck Historical Reel, 1997 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-066)
  - Ford: 14. Truck Historical Reel, 1998 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-067)
  - Ford Blue Oval Certified Program, 2001 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-068)
  - Ford Crown Victoria Spot "Last Laugh", Undated (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-069)
  - Ford Crown Victoria Spot "Last Laugh", Undated (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-070)
  - Ford Communications Network (FCN) Ford/JWT 50th Observance, 1993 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-071)
  - Ford Communications Network (FCN) News, 1993 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-072)
  - Ford Dealer Association Chairman's Convention Reel 1: Hugh Trenkamp, Ron Burns, 1990 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-073)
  - Ford Dealer Association Weekly reels 3/25, 2002 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-074)
  - Ford Focus TV (London), Undated (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-075)
  - Ford/JWT 50th Annversary Observance: Speeches by Peter Schweitzer, Burt Manning, Alex Trotman, Red Poling 20:00, 1993 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-076)
  - Ford Funding Expedition videos 19:24, 2003 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-077)
  - Ford Germany--Ford at the Geneva Motorshow, 2001 (Box 26, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-078)
  - Ford Germany--Ford Mondeo Brand Film, 2001 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-079)
  - Ford Germany--Ford of Europe Mondeo spots, Undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-080)
  - Ford Germany--Ford of Europe Norwegian Voiceovers, 2001 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-081)
  - Ford Historical Compilation, 1993 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-082)
  - Ford Historical Compilation, 1993 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-083)
  - Ford Historical Compilation, 1993 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-084)
  - Ford Japan "My First Ford" Campaign, Undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-085)
  - Ford JWT/Ford 50th Anniversary, 1993 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-086)
  - Ford Look Again Randy Newman Version, 2003 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-087)
  - Ford Look Again spots, 2003 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-088)
  - Ford Making Life Easier, 1988 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-089)
  - Ford Mondeo Brand Film, 2001 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-090)
  - Ford Motorsports and other clients compilation, Undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-091)
  - Ford Mustang Historical Part 1, 1993 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-092)
  - Ford Mustang Historical Reel, 1993 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-093)
  - Ford Mustang Historical Reel, 1993 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-094)
  - Ford Taurus, Focus, Racing, 2003 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-095)
  - Ford Thunderbird/Bond, Undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-096)
  - Ford Thunderbird "Unforgettable", 1981 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-097)
  - Ford Today Europe compilation, 1994 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-098)
  - Ford Today Europe Cycle 9 Inserts, 1995 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-099)
  - Ford Today Europe Cycle 11 Inserts, 1996 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-100)
  - Ford Today Europe Cycle 12 Inserts, Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-101)
  - Ford WCF Spots, Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-102)
  - George Black Review of European Advertising, 1986 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-103)
  - Good Old Days of Dealer TV, 1967 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-104)
  - Goodyear Aquatred "Tires of the Future", Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-105)
  - Goodyear Aquatred "Tires of the Future", Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-106)
  - Goodyear Rolling Across America Music Videos, Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-107)
  - Goodyear Rolling Across America Music Videos, Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-108)
  - Greening of Detroit, Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-109)
  - Greening of Detroit, Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-110)
  - Hines Interests Limited Partnership--One Detroit Center 14:30, 1990 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-111)
  - An Hour of the Growth of Modern Advertising, Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-112)
  - An Hour of the Growth of Modern Advertising, Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-113)
  - How to Stand Out in the Crowd--Burt Manning, 1984 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-114)
  - I Can't Get No Satisfaction, Undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-115)
  - International Reel, 1985 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-116)
  - J. Walter Does That!, 1993 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-117)
  - J. Walter Does That!, 1994 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-118)
  - J. Walter Thompson 1988 Advertising (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-119)
  - Jamie Lee Curtis BOC Press Coverage, Undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-120)
  - John O'Toole--The Future's Not What It Used to Be (AAAA), 1990 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-121)
  - Jumpstarting the Motor City: A Visual Guide to Detroit's Empowerment Zone as Seen By the People Who Live There 11:00, 1994 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-122)
  - JWT Can't Touch That and Other Spots, Undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-123)
  - JWT Worldwide Reel, 2002 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-124)
  - Kellogg's, Undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-125)
    Includes: Complete Bran Flakes, Mueslix, Frosted Bran, Nutri-Grain
  - Kellogg's: Profile of Kelloggs Objectives 15:00, Undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-126)
  - Larry Light, Horst Schulze, Maryann Keller--Chairman Convention, 1990 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-127)
  - Let Us Talk To You 8:10, 1995 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-128)
  - Lincoln LS Car of the Year, Undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-129)
  - Madden, Undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-130)
  - Madden, Undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-131)
  - Madison Ave. Satire Joe Pytka 3:30, Undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-132)
  - Many Faces of Marketing: Changing American Lifestyles and Social Trends, 1984 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-133)
  - Many Faces of Marketing: Changing American Lifestyles and Social Trends, 1984 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-134)
  - Marketing and Advertising Function, Undated (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-135)
  - Marketing and Advertising Function, Undated (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-136)
  - Media Planning and Implementation, Undated (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-137)
  - Media Planning and Implementation, Undated (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-138)
  - More Creative the Ad, The Harder It Works Part II 26:45, 1985 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-139)
  - More Creative the Ad, The Harder It Works, Undated (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-140)
  - New Life in the City: The Greening of Detroit, Undated (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-141)
  - New Life in the City: The Greening of Detroit, Undated (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-142)
  - North American Board Meeting, 1994 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-143)
  - North America Reel, 1992 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-144)
  - North America Reel, 1992 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-145)
  - Old Commercials 1947-1982, 1989 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-146)
  - Old Commercials 1947-1982, 1989 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-147)
  - Old JWT Commercials, Undated (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-148)
  - ON-Screen Entertainment--Lisa Muscio, Undated (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-149)
  - Orientation Week Part II, 1994 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-150)
  - Orientation Week Part I, 1994 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-151)
  - Peter Schweitzer Speech to Advertising Research Foundation, 1990 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-152)
  - Peter Schweitzer Brand Speech, Adcraft, 1993 (Box 30, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-153)
  - Problem Commercials: Low Awareness and Attitude Shift, 1990 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-154)
  - Red Cross focus group #2, 1993 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-155)
  - Red Cross segment "Boy is Bill Bonds Brutal", Undated (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-156)
  - Regional Advertising Group--Creative Product, Randy Albright, 1994 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-157)
  - Regional Advertising Group--Creative Product, Randy Albright, 1994 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-158)
  - Regional Advertising Group--Volunteer Program for Beard Elementary School, 1992 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-159)
  - Regional Advertising Group--Volunteer Program for Beard Elementary School, 1992 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-160)
  - Representative Public Service Spots, 1988 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-161)
    Includes: Van Patrick Memorial Invitational; Meadowbrook Music Festival; Detroit Police Safety Vest Fund; United Fund Torch Drive
  - Research Methodologies and Use, Undated (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-162)
  - Research Methodologies and Use, Undated (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-163)
  - Roger Stempel News Conference, Undated (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-164)
  - Ron Burns Address to National FDAF Chairman's Meeting, 1990 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-165)
  - Sam Snead (VPMI XII), 1988 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-166)
  - Segments with new EPT Commercials, 1992 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-167)
  - Smithsonian--On Advertising 60:00, Undated (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-168)
  - Start Me Up, Undated (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-169)
  - Talent Show Clips, New York Office 120:00, 1993 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-170)
  - Tier I and II spots, Undated (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-171)
  - Turning Home Runs into Grand Slams: The Role of PR at JWT, 1993 (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-172)
  - Toys R Us: Born to Ride, Undated (Box 31, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-173)
  - TV Advertising Seducation, Undated (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-174)
  - TV Reel, 1990 (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-175)
  - TV Show Compilation Reel, 1998 (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-176)
  - United Foundation Documentary 10:00, 1986 (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-177)
  - United Foundation spots, 1987 (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-178)
  - Van Patrick Memorial Invitational Preview 28:00, 1987 (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-179)
  - Van Patrick Memorial Invitational Preview 28:00, 1987 (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-180)
  - Van Patrick Memorial Invitational Preview: This is VPMI, 1987 (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-181)
  - Van Patrick Memorial Invitational VPMI XIII TV and Radio Arnold Palmer, Undated (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-182)
  - Van Patrick Memorial Invitational VPMI XIII TV and Radio Arnold Palmer, Undated (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-183)
  - Variety of Factors Influencing Consumer Behavior--Burial Arrangement for Family Member, Undated (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-184)
  - Victor Forbes: 4 Season Fashion Wear, Undated (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-185)
  - Videolink Demo Tape, Undated (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-186)
  - Walker/Madden Bus Television Coverage Channel 2 WJBK Detroit, 1991 (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-187)
  - Wanaume: A Voyage of Discovery (Dubai) 56:40, 2002 (Box 32, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-188)
  - WDMO Export Seminar, Undated (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-189)
  - White Castle spots, Undated (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-190)
  - White Castle What You Crave Club, 1994 (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-191)
  - White Castle What You Crave Club, 1994 (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-192)
  - White Castle What You Crave Club, 1994 (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-193)
  - White Lace (Musical group with Don Fichter), Undated (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-194)
  - WPP Presentation, 1988 (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-195)
  - Young & Rubicam--Ford Compilation, 1999 (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-196)
  - Young & Rubicam--Lincoln LS spots, 2000 (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-197)
  - Young & Rubicam--Lincoln-Mercury Ties, 2000 (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-198)
  - Young & Rubicam--Lincoln spots, 2002 (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-199)
  - Zubi/Hispanic Ford Advertising, 2003 (Box 33, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-200)
- Optical Media (CDs, DVDs), 1999-2003; 2
  - Ford--Dealer Ad Planner: Vehicle Art A Pictorial CD Index. Disc 1: Car/SUV, 2001 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-001)
  - Ford--Dealer Ad Planner: Vehicle Art A Pictorial CD Index. Disc 2: Truck, 2001 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-002)
  - Ford--Explorer Ads, 2002 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-003)
  - Ford--Explorer Artwork, Sin Limites, 2002 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-004)
  - Ford--Ford Dealer Advertising Planner CD Pictorial Index. Disc One: Cars, 2000 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-005)
  - Ford--Ford Dealer Advertising Planner CD Pictorial Index. Disc Two: Trucks, 2000 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-006)
  - Ford--No boundaries Ford Outfitters Model Year 2000, 1999 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-007)
  - Ford--Spring Madness Sales Event Advertising Support, 2003 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-008)
  - Ford--WDMO Ford Company Art, 1999 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-009)
  - Lincoln--Ad Planner, 2001 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-010)
  - Lincoln--Ad Planner, 2002 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-011)
  - Mercury--Ad Planner, 2001 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-012)
  - Mercury--Ad Planner Supplement Including 2002 Mountaineer and New Action Photography, 2001 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-013)
  - Mercury--Ad Planner, 2002 (Box 34, Video-disc RL11360-OP-014)
- Documents and supporting materials, 1967-2003 and undated; 3
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 34)
  - RL11360-BCAM-013, 2000 (Box 34)
  - RL11360-UMATIC-001 through UMATIC-178, 1967-2003 and undated (Box 34)
  - RL11360-UMATIC-054, 1991 (Box 34)
  - RL11360-VHS-005 through VHS-196, 1967-2003 and undated (Box 34)